https://www.ionabooks.com/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
1.       Introduction
1.1    We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors.
1.2    This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.
1.3    We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.
1.4    In this policy, “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Wild Goose Publications / The Iona Community.[ For more information about us, see Section 13.]
2.       Credit
2.1    This document was created using a template from SEQ Legal (https://seqlegal.com).
3.       How we use your personal data
3.1    In this Section 3 we have set out:
(a)    the general categories of personal data that we may process;
(b)    in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data;
(c)    the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
(d)    the legal bases of the processing.
3.2    We may process website “usage data“. The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is the google analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.
3.3    We may process information that you post for publication on our website (“publication data“). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website. The legal basis for this processing is your consent at the time of posting images or information via the website contact form.
3.4    We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us (“enquiry data“). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of providing responses to enquires made by your through the website. The legal basis for this processing is your consent at the time of enquiry.
3.5    We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (“notification data“). The notification data may be processed[for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
3.6    We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“correspondence data“). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and communications with users.
3.7    We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.
3.8    We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of the community council against risks].
3.9    In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 3, we may also process [any of your personal data] where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
3.10  Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.
4.       Providing your personal data to others
4.1    In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
5.       International transfers of your personal data
5.1    In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
5.2    The hosting facilities for our website are situated in London. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of the United Kingdom. Transfers to the United Kingdom will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission.
5.3    You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.
6.       Retaining and deleting personal data
6.1    This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.
6.2    Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.
6.3    In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on the following criteria:
(a)    the period of retention of personal data will be determined based on your consent to hold an account on our website and/or to receive newsletters.
6.4    Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
7.       Amendments
7.1    We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.
7.2    You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.
7.3    We may notify you of significant changes to this policy by email.
8.       Your rights
8.1    In this Section 8, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.
8.2    Your principal rights under data protection law are:
(a)    the right to access;
(b)    the right to rectification;
(c)    the right to erasure;
(d)    the right to restrict processing;
(e)    the right to object to processing;
(f)    the right to data portability;
(g)    the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
(h)    the right to withdraw consent.
8.3    You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.
8.4    You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.
8.5    In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
8.6    In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.
8.7    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
8.8    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.
8.9    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.
8.10  To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:
(a)    consent; or
(b)    that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,
and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
8.11  If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.
8.12  To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.
8.13  You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us OR by email.
9.       About cookies
9.1    A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
9.2    Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.
9.3    Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.
10.    Cookies that we use
10.1  We use cookies for the following purposes:
(a)    authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website
(b)    status – we use cookies [to help us to determine if you are logged into our website
(c)    security – we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally
(d)    analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and
(e)    cookie consent – we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally
11.    Cookies used by our service providers
11.1  Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.
11.2  We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
12.    Managing cookies
12.1  Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:
(a)    https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
(b)    https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);
(c)    http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);
(d)    https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
(e)    https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
(f)    https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).
12.2  Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.
12.3  If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.
13.    Our details
13.1  This website is owned and operated by Wild Goose Publications.
13.2  We are registered in Scotland, and our registered office is at:
Wild Goose Publications
The Iona Community
21 Carlton Court
Glasgow G5 9JP
13.4  You can contact us:
(a)    by post, to the postal address given above;
(b)    using our website contact form;
(d)    by email, using the email address published on our website from time to time
Using Our Materials
E-Postcards
Newsletter Archive
Shipping costs
Copyrights
An oral history of the Iona community
Rebuilding the Abbey
The Community and Africa
Select Month
April 2012  (1)
December 2011  (3)
March 2009  (529)
To receive our weekly newsletter please enter
The Iona Community is:
An ecumenical movement of people from different walks of life and different traditions in the Christian church.
Committed to the gospel of Jesus Christ, and to following where that leads, even into the unknown.
Engaged together, and with people of goodwill across the world, in acting, reflecting and praying for justice, peace and the integrity of creation.
Convinced that the inclusive community it seeks must be embodied in the community it practises.
Contact details As all staff are currently working from home, the best way to contact us is by email to admin@ionabooks.com
Wild Goose Publications
The Iona Community
21 Carlton Court
Glasgow G5 9JP
Tel. +44 (0)141 429 7281
E mail: admin@ionabooks.com
Scottish Charity Reg. No. SC003794
Limited Company Reg. No. SC096243
For a wider range of Wild Goose Resource Group material or to contact them directly, visit their own website: www.wildgoose.scot
Additional LinksGet in touch
Using Our Materials
Shipping Costs
FAQ
Privacy Policy
Terms and Conditions
Newsletter Archive
An Oral History of the Iona Community
Mobile Phone – web app A short prayer or reflection for each day, taken from our publications, which shows up on your mobile phone at the tap of an icon. You can also email the thought to friends.
Go to www.ionabooks.com/m/ on your phone and then make a handy icon for your phone by creating a shortcut or bookmark. To see your daily thought, just tap the icon each day.
For those without phones with an internet capability, you can view the daily thoughts on your computer by going to www.ionabooks.com/m/
Copyright 2020 © Wild Goose PublicationsSite by: artis digital
Books
Advent & Christmas
Care For Creation
Healing
Iona
Iona Community Classics
Issues & Inspirations
John Bell & Wild Goose Resource Group
E- LITURGIES & PRAYERS
AdoptionAdvent & ChristmasAffirmationsAgapéAgeingAIDSAll Hallows'All Saints' DayAll Souls' DayAll-age resourcesAngelsAnimalsAscensionAsh WednesdayBaptismBibleBirthBlessing of childrenBlessingsBullyingCandle prayersCandlemasChrist the King SundayChristian unityChristingleChurchCity livingColumbaCommitmentCommunionCreation & EnvironmentDaily lifeDaily readingsDeathDifficult timesDivorceEaster SundayEpiphanyEveningFather's DayFoodForgivenessFriendshipFuneralsGeneralGood FridayGospel storiesGrandparenthoodHarvestHealingHolocaustHoly SpiritHoly WeekHome and exileHomelessnessHospitalityIdentity & DifferenceInterfaithIonaIona Abbey servicesIona Prayer CircleJusticeLaughterLeavingLent & EasterLGBTLightLoveMaundy ThursdayMeditationsMoneyMorningMothering SundayMusic (sheet music)New YearOld TestamentPalm SundayParenthoodPartnershipPeacePentecostPilgrimagePovertyPrayerPrisoners of consciencePromisesRacismReconciliationRefugeesRelationship breakdownRemembrance DayRogationSafetySaints & othersSeasons & FestivalsSexualityShrove TuesdaySlavery & freedomSongsSoulSpringThanksgivingTransfigurationTransitionTransportTrinity SundayValentine's DayWaterWeddingWelcomeWomenWork & leisureWorkshopsYouth
Music & Song Downloads
Music (audio)
Music (sheet music)
Words-only songs
CDs & DVDs
CDs – audiobooks & performance
CDs – Music
Iona DVDs
Living the Questions DVDs
E-Postcards
Gift Vouchers
Log in
Lost your password?
Register
Email address *
Password *
Subscribe to our newsletter
Your personal data will be used to support your experience throughout this website, to manage access to your account, and for other purposes described in our privacy policy.
Register
